Good afternoon.
Raise your hand you cannot hear me right so I was one thank you very
much for coming I know it's all the way of your third-floor I'm really happy to see all these people I'm
guessing...hardcore gamers if you worked all the way up here so,
thank you very much for coming.
As I was preparing for today I was thinking about this yesterday I actually did the...is three hundred
...two days ago that right here in this building I was here at
...about the vision for building games for windows so,
leader year-ago as anybody here flashier.
See if you comebacks...as you think and, we percent inhibition and I talked about these vision where you
as again publisher would be able to write a game once.
Publisher into our store once and then...go occurs a myriad of devices at the
time I was just happy telling people about...you know, going to be email to
going-to windows phone tablet desktop and
division for xbox it's been a year and not only have we got here you saw that from the cuter
today but we also...holies so, it's super...for me because today
...windows stand we now have one operating system that...that goes across all
the myriad of devices from microsoft and we have one platform the universal windows
...going-to be here...about for the next three days that can...you target all of these devices
...one unifier application model now how many of you have written
a windows phone app before or windows store where consulate before.
So, all of you raise your hand
you're already familiar with this platform it took us three years together hereand,
the benefit is you been using it when you think about the universal windows platform you should think of
our like this it's nothing but the aggregation of all the best features occurs all
of our existing platforms that we had before if you new windows phone if you
no-win rt that's what universal winner platform is it's a little bit of an iteration
its data aggregation and is that unification that you're
going to get so, draw the session we're going to cramp quite a bit of content and,
we're going to lever at some of the things that you already know...against evangelist microsoft
...would mis...he's going to do all the heavy lifting today so the...make sure you
...for him because he's going to do all the coding of all I get to do are this lights and, if you them
of so we're going to spend the next hour talking about window stan and how you can get the most
...windows...for...games and in some cases we're going to play the role
of tour guide where we can actually just tell you hey there's these really cool feature you
sugar the session and learn everything about that session because some of the topics that we need to talk
about cover a whole hour and their
...build your here...we're just going to point you there and have you go there in other
cases where we think are things or features that are very relevant for games we're going to
...beep and give you code samples and give you a little bit of everything you need to know so,
it's rather again what you throughout the session
...you should expect is going to talk about this features then we're going to show you how to migrated
your windows phone or your windows storegame onto the universal
windows platform and then we're going to take advantage of new features such as xbox live so,
we're going to go pretty quick bear with us
as we go before I go there I do have to give you kind of a demo of
...windows tony's about from a gamer perspective hopefully everybody saw today
...everybody's hopefully saw today...via the keno...you saw how, for example,
now we have action center windows...really great way to engage users right
as gamers we've always done that where we send notification we tell user say come back you have
...thirty seventy two hours etc now...action...those are there you saw
joe be talk about discovery how with...windows store now your games we promoter a
lot more the icon is very prominent if you see the star screen right here to store icon is
quite prominence so when we promote games people are going to click on them and you're going to get your
...right so it's a great thing for us to have safety...out all of these...from
...today so let me show you some...things that you didn't see one of these
over-doing for gamers is were bringing the xbox experience onto windows
stand and windows phone these right here's the xbox app if
anybody here splayed and consul you're probably familiar with these application on consul you get some of the
...you get to see all of these functionality on the consul every day
what you see here is if I go home you see right here this is where we're at
I have all my activity feed these are all the people that I follow when they comment
and something when they share a video when they...and achievement I get to see all
...activities this is really useful to-you as a game publisher because this is how people
discover your games I can come here click on a friend and see what
airplane I can see what my friends are earning achievements on obviously as we compete
as a new as we play together I get to see a lot of that but here I can also see
it with people I follow I could see a lot more of the activity throughout I can also
...with my friends so here you can see that you can chat with your friends and here you can talk
to them regardless of whether there
an xbox or windows or phone so we're bringing that social graph and
...everywhere so each with us throughout the day that will be a lot more engagement we
were actually cramming last night and one of the friends was being...hearsay hey how are you going to play
a play tonight literally we were actually working through some of the sessions so,
we were like hey no we can do anything today you can see achievements to you can see all
source of activity you can discover...new games by just
...what your friends are doing throughout the applications so it's really,
really excited to see all of these come and be with you
throughout a continuous experience wherever you go you'll be able to carry this with you and you'll be able to engage.
Another feature that you have
...you see right here is obviously game dvr everybody here has hopefully seen game
dvr and xbox one in the last year so super popular...to...you know,
now we...and all of the other companies that are doing video online is becoming forgave
mrs becoming one of those mass have features...bringing it onto the desktop and only
can you can see here that I have some good tvs...recorded on these
bc have the ones that I...from online to write and I sure I have the ones that I
can see from my community but the one that I want to show you hear it also has the ones that I recorded on
this pc which means now you will be able to or users will be able to record
your get your games from within windows stan let me show you how that works.
Right here have mine...this is classic
mine craft away hopefully all of you played in the last ten years you know,
me and my kid used to play this for five years ago he wanted me to let, you know,
he did not have any coach I did not have any coaching from him these are my skills
you're going to see or my lack of scales to be were...what he said but this is
microbe this is not a windows synapse this is not a universal lap this up
has been around forever everybody knows it...and without me touching and
...anything I can come here and just well as first luncheon.
And, when it comes argues...these pres windows g to open game
bar this is a feature the system level because I have that xbox up now I have that game
...the system level now it's ava a previously
before identified is a game when we had any fighting's as games the game
or automatically come up if you have a game that's...and is not yet declared to be a game in
the user will be able to just come here...windows g and get the game bar and from the game by
you-can lance...up you can actually recorder captures
...you can see some of the settings right here for my recording so I can
comptroller right here from within the game bar there's a lot more servicing the xbox up I showed you earlier so
quality and everything you have a lot of control over all that so again my
craft classic mine crafts?
No, tricks no anything right here that we've actually I'm trying resize it but my
mom's here not collaborating this surface right here is shining hopefully you can
see from there so now I can just go right here impress windows...which, you know,
we lucky...shortcuts right there
it's recording the game if I wanted to show maybe my mom how to do something like create
their own world I can come back here and it's recording and now I'm capturing I can just go in there
...the world and let's go into creative
mode because you'll be new like I am and,
you see...is just recording it's all happening if I want to toggle the timer so because I don't want to
see it I'm going to maybe record for a few minutes windows of to you will toggle itnow my
...is their strike or my...there so I can go back and you recorded and, right there
was not scripted...you experience but you can see there it's recording and then I
can go back here and go out to my xbox up and see all my recordings
there this one somehow because it's interesting because it...I want in saved.
It survey...there in the middle of...it let's go back to the xbox up and see which
shape one...pc rather...from so he was there are
some refreshing there and you see the recording that we had an uses right here can actually click on
...recording actually treatment and then nodding the xbox
...have today the one that you'll be able to get with the...this week you also be able to share from right here
from within the app users will be able to share and that's how they're going to promote your game everybody's going
to see a discovery its...ecosystem that feeds itself and,
this is coming again onto windows then
it's very feature-rich if you look at the same functionality that we have.
...give you this.
If you look at the functionality that we have.
Owners slide missing here...have...different
...that is very feature-rich like I showed you features like activity I show you
...have I showed you chat I show you game dvr all those features are
there and windows stan a...features are also windows phone ten
on windows phone so you'll be able to get a lot of the same features on windows phone and,
we're actually making sure that we keep as much...as we can across all of our experiences so,
phone right now the only thing that's missing from
phonemes game dvr if you get the windows ten bits of the windows phone ten bits you're not going
to have game dvr there is something that we're looking at we're trying to figure out what the right experience would be there
forforgave dvr and phone but it's something we continue to explore and you should expect improvements
...so all those features right there you didn't have to a single line of code you
didn't have to do a universal lap you didn't have to do anything and you're already going to benefit from that?
Now there's other things are going to get just from moving on to win the stand,
for example, when you bring your game...windows...you can now start running on direct
...you recompile and you start putting your game to understand you'll get benefits from the platform itself
this kind of operating system and platform features that you're going to get that you don't have...a
...coda hopefully here everybody in the...familiar with
...twelve right we announced last year these are new api for directory
...direct...twelve would you get is a lot more control over how you
render we have optimized are largely make sure that you have a lot of control and how you
...the gpu so you can optimize rendering quite a bit
...squeeze every ounce of performance from all of your games
now if you're like me and you're right higher-level games like you ride on unity
and real or any other higher-level frameworks miller's
...all the middle providers are ready using direct
...and you're going to benefit from everything they do so in your case you're just going to get the
benefit for free you get more performance you'll get better rendering for free by just using libraries that
already taken advantage of direct and other area where we made significant improvements the use
of developer would benefit from just from moving to understand is...case...the case
or significantly larger today than they were a year-ago just for context you I
don't have the numbers because they're never accurate and we were shy about it but just for context
...grew over...thousand new api think about it we brought in aps from consul
we were aps from phone we had all these windows api already so we do over
...thousand api that's probably one of our largest updates ever and that's just...the
...tci on the dominates
...we also...about two thousand api is and,
what we did there is remember we have different profile so we have...on the desktop and we brought a
lot of those api says to the you windows store today actual universal
platform so that you would have better compatibility across right if you seen the profiles
...a few classes that people are saying well I wish I could use this class over there so I don't have
thread my code and I can share more coded desktops we've done that we brought in two thousand and we will
continue to bring more api as we go forward now...and...in we can actually
ad api much faster than we've ever been before in the past it's always been
...all we cannot do that because we are
...a hole in the framework which sliding now we can start adding more libraries for
you as we go and will continue to do these as we go and the last one that I want to highlight is the
wing thirty-two and comic...this one special to me because here we
brought only about a thousand api...but those api are ones that really,
really matter for asses gamers this is some of the work that we've done
...the last year with unity and unreal and marmalade...of middleware
is an...media and other part is...related to gaming the came and said look the universe
...platform is great but I really wish we had these api stings that matter a lot,
for example, threading?
Sockets right if you are here two years ago and you hear about platform you are lego
...sockets that's weird right and we didn't make sense to all of us
...gamers he was a pain to have to rewrite well we've heard you were bringing all those backs and those are
the thousand api so even to the number is not...standing it's a number that really,
really matters heap virtual-memory things that we are really,
really hard to do if you don't get the...system level api so those are the ones that we
focused on I'm not going to talk much about media but,...because there's a lot of sessions and
bil about it but,
to improvements I wanted high...low latency video low latency audio that's common
pain and...decrees latency is down to...so for those of you who have in the
past I've really one lower latency audio we no longer buffer so you can really control how much
...there and how like how low your latency is...we also added a myriad of...api
...there...have a session tomorrow and, we always my big favor some make sure you come to
you session tomorrow you'll hear about the favor laterif you want to learn more about direct text twelve
...mcmillan has a session also tomorrow and he'll go diving
...and give you the update on the aps have changed from last year and how we are with
regards to shipping this year which is pretty much done and,
we have really great support from media amd and all of
the our providers now moving on to the universal windows platform?
Everybody who's been here had...before his...before has at some point
seen the slide this is actually the new universal windows platforms
...showing around I saw these lie five years ago when we introduce windows phone
...these light three years ago when we call the winner t the point here is the platform
...change everything that we have in here there's a lot of
...don't get me wrong I can go in there to...you go through sessions and
build the rescission up model and you'll go in and care about new background in api
...packaging and you're going
to hear about how we increase the package sizes of the now we can fit any game because the package
...sizes are so large...via social in the store and we gotta talk about the one store
...session on tools are going to talk about graphics the bloggers and all sorts of different tools
...coming for game so he's the exact same platform your familiar and...continue to
...just because I'm not going to spend a lot of time and these
...before you'll have three days full of sessions here and there's some
sessions that I highlighted as a reference here and you'll see them as a reference at the end at the end of the
presentation let's go to our games because that's what we want to get into so we're going to
...game from windows store on to windows...and that's where
...introduces two-game I can do that switch over to my machine so this is
a game that we...to really simple demo in the whole point of the demo
...to teach students how to write video games so you're not going to see the most flashy
...follows thing ever here it's going to be very simple game so we have here to start is
...show you the game running as a windows eight application in windows ten so
...here to run the app as it exists you can see it starts off and you can hear the
background music somewhere coming out of the here that okay I don't know if it's in my hedges
I played so much organs actually coming out of a speaker so you can tell this is a windows
...app on windows ten because at the top left you get the hamburger menu that has what used to be on the charms
...get the button over on the right that allows you to put
...full-screen which is how windows runtime...used to run they were always bolstering
but because this is windows ten is actually lives in a window you can move it around the
strength so what we need to do is to turn this into a windows
...so to do that what I did was I created a new universal
app project and I brought my code over I didn't I didn't change anything I literally just
...and pasted the code as we go for a add a link over here and we have the
exact same code running just with the universal wrapper radish basically as a new package
manifest and whatnot so if I run this version of the app as a windows ten app.
I showed you on the phone first because.
The...similar to windows eight,
you know, the phone always runs full-screen there are no windows there are no concept
...so you can see this is now running in the windows ten phone emulator as universal
lab I can go in here and I can actually play the game all tap start so
it's a very simple game you very as simple...game here a little blue monster
I'm controlling the read monster chasing the around the glowing icons in the corners
are windows ten features and the point of the exerciser students is that every time they add
a new windows ten feature to the game...new icon as well so your goal is to run around and eat those
of glowing icons because they're worth more points than the regular dots
...you can see runs on in windows phone and everything is happy...a full-screen app
but when you move to windows ten there are other considerations to deal with windows yep.
...we can switch.
We got this switch back and area so, windows stand
write-in windows a...tools...you could snap...he was always full-screen your
apt enough to worry about windows, windows stand first of all you still have control
so if you...your game to run a full-screen great we give you are api that you can program marilee
call...screen mode right if you...your api
two-run a specific aspect ratio we give you an api that can...hey here's my preferred size here's
my minimum size...give you a lot of control that said ultimate control
...with the user so the user can at some point decide look I'm going to
...these we know from here over here and I'm going to put it right here and he's going to be decides
therefore as you ride or as you make as you move your move your game from windows eight on to
...ten you will have to support window
and if you do support window in we recommend that you actually, you know,
make sure you handle full-screen...and, another thing that you actually have to do
...support activation in the activation now we run in windowed the user can have
to windows and you-are-there your baseball and then the user goes in and clicks on email or, you know,
whatever it is facebook...a message or something and you lost focus and you need to make sure you...
you games so you need to make sure you handle the activated and the activated event in your game and,
it's pretty...so brand one you add that to the games which back over and show you how to do that so this is
the same project haven't changed anything which toggle back and forth ...in a jump into the main
...a model game application amount of game games if you're familiar with the architecture
their this will be familiar to you so the first thing we're going to do here roger let me-let me run
it without making a single code change so you'll see it running in windows ten in a window.
So, it starts up that this was the last size that the window when the user
close the application this was the size that they had the window so you can dragging to make a bigger smaller but,
for example, we can come in here and say we want to have always...at
a specific size so there's a new class that exists here in windows ten called application
view if you look at the intelligence on this we get a few things here we can set
the preferred launch size we can set the preferred when doing mode and things like that but we're after
is we're going to get the view for the application view for the current window...a culture
I resize...going to pass in a new size and I'm going to this game resin nineteen twenty by ten eighty-some
...in fifty percent of that so it's going to run basically...window that's about half the size of the screen
...see this is called try resize view will find a variety of these method methods that start with
try...return boolean to you so you can tell whether or not you successfully
resize reason for this is...resize you doesn't necessarily make sense all
platforms you can't resize the window and phone calls phone is always full-screen when you're in
tablet mode on a touch device everything is always full-screen so this is an
...exception will just tell you all I didn't change view so if you need to do something because of that I
failed so with that in place we can run the app now you'll see the app
resize so we'll start out a certain screen size and then shrink?
Or growth order actually I'm probably was already at that size
let me go ahead and make the window bigger and close.
So, it saves that new size...again.
And, I see the window...shrunk down to that specific size that we set as
a couple of things that hang off if...this is
try resize view we can set we can figure out if they if it's been snapped the left
side or snap to the right side of the screen we can get the title bar inset the title bar we can
set that preferred minimum size and one of the a variety of things here that you can mess around with.
So, that's the way to resize...thing we want to...full-screen visit the game
issued you...support full-screen so I've already...a little bit of code here to handle the input so
...I'm listening for the f eleven key so my input manager class here
will let-me know when someone has press the f eleven key and when that happens again I'm
a use that same application view object and I'm going to check the is full-screen
...this is true already in full-screen if it's false we need
enter full-screen so simple toggle here if we're full-screen we're going to...full-screen
mode if we're not we're going to enter full-screen mode again you'll see here there's another method with
...try so this is going to return boolean that's going to tell you whether or not it succeeded?
So, if we run the app this way you'll see it'll start out in a window.
And, I can press eleven here
...to full-screen press...eleven toggle back.
Just that simple to do it of course you can, you know, call this the
...you...as the preferred method whatever you want
...but always give the user the option to be able to toggle back and forth everything here is a window
now and not everything leaves and full-screen world so in the final thing is highly mention was activation
...activation so
model game handles this a little bit for us so let me show you the code as it exists and model game in the
game window class so what they do is hook into core window every windows eight
and windows ten application has a core window and there's a dot activated event so we're going to
hook that event and basically check the windows activated...arts here if it...to
the activated we set our is our global is active property to false
if it comes...activated we said is active true so
whoops back in my code here all on comment this junk?
I check here in my update loop if I'm active then I'm going to resume any sound
effects that I had...from becoming the activated and I'm going to call the logic in order to update my
spring.
Otherwise if I'm not active I'm going to pause all sound effects and...update isn't going to happen because it's not part of
...so many turn the music back on here say...able to.
Here the music start and stop.
...the app with this in place.
So, annoying title screen...a we go back to visual studio music stops go back to the
...music
continue you can see here we'll start the game let the monster run to a certain position.
And, we'll stop music stop...a couple seconds we go back you'll see the read monster will be and exact spot
...it...worth handling the activated enrollment.
So, that's window and bets full-screen and that is
...activate nutshell.
Jump back to
...literally that's all you have to do...lines of code most games actually work but they will be
...navigation and window in on friday so-if you want-to go and every little detail and
api...a...great...friday that of...deliver nice...rehearsal
...was really great now that's half the work the...
as telling you how to handle when knowing is not the heavy lifting you will still have to come up with
the design strategy for-you game...to decide well when
...full-screen I want to scale the content or maybe I want to create an adaptive layout or I want, you know,
be...responsive design...fluid...flow certain things...that takes a whole
hour but, the viewed at the...you is that we've already recorded that add
...a month-and-a-half ago we told williams from the fable team cayman...
session the say hey here's, you know, what you need to think about here's all the options...you should be considering
so, watch the whole session and then from there you'll come up with the strategy the platform supports everything and
... the way I think about games most guys will have maybe a combination like in some cases you'll just
want to scale but often you'll have to do scaling and either and,
that adaptive layout or something else along with a along with it so,
...platform support everything and you don't have to do lab a huge amount of rework because
you've been thinking about these problems wherever in other platforms and it's going to be able to...you
can be able to bring those same patterns on to our platform no problem I just wanted to point out the video from
...because it's really useful now the next thing window
in the beginning the next thing we talked about when we did the outline was...
we are handle input and, we thought about two things the first one is
...what's...pointer or what change and mouse in touch if you remember windows
windows store two years ago we came back we said look we're always going to
make touch seamless along with mouse so we're going to aggregate those into these one class
called pointer api and regardless of where the user I use in touch or whether
...mouse it's all going to pointer so as long as you handle pointer you'll be taken care of and if you've
been writing games you been using this pattern for the last two years nothing there changes with the universal
in this platform we've added some really cool features to inc and other area so we've added improvements but for
your games he didn't have to change anything in the game so there was nothing to say right there on
miles and
...and touch so moving on to text we have a lot of improvements
and text them I spend a lot of...in the last two years
...other platforms and windows and...was one of my biggest paints has anybody ever
here like how to do text on their games and then have to maybe
hackett text box where you put a hidden textbook somewhere and you just that focus to it
...would come out right or some of as we go as far as you know,
pretending to be a textbook throughout summation peer and actually doing that most of those
work-arounds were solvable and they worked but it was always clergy and always feel like there's gotta
be an easier way to do it and today with the universal windows platform we have
the easier way to do it here's we're going to give you there's an input...class?
And, that input campaign class you have control over when you show it you have
...when you hide it when you do show it when we do show it or even when the user
tops on with touch and...comes up you get...that says this is
showing so now, you know, how to affect your game you can parser game you also get the coordinate system
if the input...is dot you get...sizes hey here's how much of the area we're going to
include so you have full control over how you handle keyboard no, more
of those hacks no more of that code and it's relatively easy to shows...when we go ahead and code that
yep so have you noticed on the menu for my game there was an option for enter name where you can put in your name and
the character role recognize us that name puts it up in the score display so to do that I've got a
very simple dialogue box that I wrote it's all written model game it's not a windows
dialogue box and basically what I call the show method from my game I called input
...current wvu dot try show and when I call hide of my dialogue box I call try
...again these are try method to get the boolean it tells you whether or not it's available or whether out
...succeeded and the reason for this is if you're on a desktop and you have a keyboard connected
it's not going to pop-up advice there's like a...the input...touch-screen it's not going to
...the input painters you can't touch and on touch-screen screen so in this case
...I'm going to do is I'm going to set my laptop here to tablet mode so the app now we'll start-up in a
full screen mode and intel motives when you'll see
...the stupid music and go down to enter name...pop up and now I can
type my name in this box and you see shows up in the top right corner presenter and what's
right is this response to all the standard keyboard events that you're already used to so if you've already
written regain to support keyboard you already...game to support input...you just actually need to show in
...that's all I need to...very simple?
To lines of code ic...some friends that are work within the past and we've implemented adoration
...was couple hundred lines of code
...know reference moi that was good advice the time
...reference ...even now we've got in there and it's in the platform
...to user going forward so another area would input of
course is now that we have these myriad these huge family of devices we need to worry about the
controller and, here's a good example of where we bring and how the universal
...platform brings the best stuff from everywhere we've always had...input on the desktop pretty popular
great api servers well for a few years is very simple...powerful
now the xbox had a game pad class and they been working...for the last
...years is more modern it has in my opinion a better object model it was more future proof for
...we felt like hey we gotta bring the best
of breed api and this was a hard choice because we were like lx employees use everywhere it's on desktop
...all that but we finally said hey, you know, game...is the better api is the one that we're
getting best into the future so let's bring that...the universal...platform and that's
we're going-to we're going-to be using going forward now with the game
...julio to support and all platforms a windows mobile desktop xbox
one all of them we supported but if we come up with a new classroom later
...comptroller make sense we're going to use these api and this is the one they were
going to stick to so you'll be able to continue leverage the knowledge and the coded you
have the api feature-rich so multiple game
paths headset everything that you expect...from the game part is all there now for those of you that we're
using x...what we've done is we said look we don't want you to
throw-away all your code so why don't we rapid...a little wrapper
input was very simple it only have five met that so we create a wrapper that actually goes
...underneath the seen it actually uses all the game
...api but it gives you the method signatures for ex inputs...our way for you...
you include the header you just swapped library that...link against and you're done right so very easy for you
...your game and very easy for you actually reuse your
...without doing anything now I do have to give you a caveat on the bills are going
to get this week game part is not in their the api
...but they're not implemented so again just wait a little bit until the first
flied or the next slide where this comes in and then you'll be able to have them by
rpm it's a very simple api anybody here has been used in
xbox is the exact same api as we didn't change the name so you'll be able to user code very easily?
...there we could be done but they tell us we...feel a sixty-minutes words that.
In my opinion you just handle everything you need to have a good game right you had a good
game plea to begin with even to o'brien's is questionable...simple by
the sine but we had a template to begin with so we added the window in we added all the
input...there we can start taking advantage of new features and here
we go ahead and go for the big enchilada the
release huge innovation that we have for gamers on...stand and that's xbox
...everybody here's familiar with expert live services right.
It's rx...you know, one social graphics are network
...services that have been proven the scale they've been really,
really solid we have lessons or a...several years of...learning api so let me tell
you...bringing onto windows first of all were obviously bring in identity and social right so you
bo...profile uc their social graph you'll see
their game pleats pretty much everything that I show you on that xbox up all of
that functionality comes without any and profile and you're going to get all that.
The next never bringing is the data platforms so that if you want to write achievements in get
...activity and do a lot with the data
you'll also get all that and then the last time we think that
...you is multiplayer now if you're familiar with expert
...that's everything so we're bringing all the services were giving you the same api
or equivalent api...and you'll have feature parity as we go across the obviously
will do the right thing by the form factor would not everything makes sense and every device
...our intent is to bring there's many things as we can such that the platform you know,
benefits from and having the feature and he doesn't that you're
meant to the overall experience because we won the user to have a great experience across
the whole device family so, we
...bryan how hard is it to add xbox live onto our
game it's pretty simple so xbox live right now is distributed as a
new get package so you download that and I've already done the done the back and workers can
see my packages dot configure I have a reference to...xbox live sdk so the
...that makes sense to do when you're reading your...you want to have people sign it
...you want to get their profiler gamer tag...that information so that's what we'll do this game so
extremely simple you grab the user object
here listen microsoft xbox services system call sign in
...that's going to return to you and xbox user object
welcome from there the next thing we need is an xbox live context for that
user the context object is basically your interface for every service that you
...talk to so you create one simply by
doing it and passing in the user that you want associated with the context?
And, then to pullback...information...going to call into the profile service as I said all these live off of
context if we look at intel...the...service leader board matchmaking
presence every service lives off of context so we're use the profile service and call get
user profile asic passing in the xbox user id of the person that we just signed
it we're going...back from there is a profile object and
off the profile object you can grab a variety of things...
You can get the account...serve their gold or silver you can get their current gamer score
they're gamer tag they're user id the xbox
user id which is just a unique identifier that identifies them to xbox live.
So, what we care about is the gamer tag we're going to sign that to our gamer tag property and the gamer pick
...display both of those things in the top right corner of our screen gamer pick as handed to you as a
url so you can actually look at this in the bagger launch internet
explore spar in hit that you are eyeing you'll get
their full-size gamer pick so I just wrote a tracker code here that converted to something that
model gain can use which is a texture...and I sign that to my gamer
...so if I go back to my original monster game here I'm going to on comment
...line that sciences in...live manager
...all the xbox live stuff into this xbox live manager clashes to keep it all-in-one
place?
So, if we run this you'll see that were going to login it's going to
log in with the microsoft account of the user that...into windows ten when you set up
...actually...a log in the live id you type in your...microsoft account formally
library formally passport formally seventeen other things...in with that and that's one that gets
...the application now if you are domain user a local user will...instead of
say hey what live id with microsoft account should not use for this and you can type that in, you know,
for...for that application and it gets...to that...you can see here we already login we've got the gamer tag this is
...account so it's kind of cryptic name to it and my one of my favorite
...picks the picture of the angry toast so.
Really three lines of code to login to xbox live...pullback
...profile information of the user these could really matters can everybody
...just want-to make sure because these are three lines of code...we go forward these...lines we want to remember
...in the back...
Okay,...and context your profile.
So, I want to highlight before moving to the next slide I do want to highlight out there's a really grateful one-hour
session again we do neurology see by the way all over again content this year
not...everything that we have to announcer the whole year we announcer gc
...sixteen hours a videos and channel nine go there and watch it if you were the keno today and
you're thinking hey where's all the gaming content of it was done a month ago
gc feels printers...stage shared...vision were super excited so
make sure you go out go back and watch a lot of that if you're feeling like hey I want to dive deeper
into games and build is all about help you...deeper into the platform we have these over
your session so we can point you do that but you should be watching that you can get the most out of it in this
k bj the principle pm who manages these api had
a really great session that we learn everything from that so we...app and,
he was a three or four...three or four weeks ago so literally within a couple days of watching
these video we were up and running once we got there is the get so.
...so we have profile we want to have data right we want to have achievements we
want to have lead aboard we'll have that so, what I want to do is I want explain you how the data platform
and xbox live works just because it's really cool and then you'll see some of
that from ryan's code snippets here's how it works first of all you...game and when you run
...game you define a set of events and, you know,
the set of data that you want to collect securing control of what over what-you want-to do and,
you actually define the data and...to...through the...and, the advantage there's a case
rather just listening you don't have to do anything you don't have to worry about communicating back to server you don't
have to do anything you know, cryptic you just pass it on to the
...pool and they are robotically pass it on to xbox live on the cloud so,
from here on all degree encode you don't have to...which is really good because as
would hire stuff is that's where they several years' worth of work that we've invested into a rely as
we have a data receiver that, you know, is actually just leasing in for all those events they pass it on
to a stats engine that's actually interprets all that data and then
that's engine actually manages and says these are going to...this is going to...aboard,
you know,...from there we also the right...and then if you...some of the data back you can actually get back to
real-time activity right so again all of the
green staff dusty have released thing that's a heavy lifting
that's xbox live that stuff you don't have to worry about your overhearing control of
hey these are the events I want to do and then you later on go back and find your achievements and you go back
...find all the things that you one-d user to half these are also means the
...such that you can go in there to find your events and your data and later on
ad achievements or tweak on the back-end how you games
...right because we don't have to all we're doing is passing the data and there's the starts engine that's
...and say one they...hundred in these they're going to reach these achievement are going to achieve they're going to
...achievement so you don't have to worry about all that when you...game that way they don't have to download
another five gigabytes of data edges because you change achievements or anything like that and your game so, that's
...data platform is very cool and, let's see we can do it achievements right...
...show a sample are how to do leader boards and achievement so I've defined a leader
...I've defined event data for my game as I said it can be anything I had
to be the number of times the ...many dot soybeans that's kind of like my score
so I've got data already that's that leaves up on xbox live it already
lives in my leader board we just want to display the leader board on the screen so to do that
...not switch there we go...which.
Have a method here called get...board a single right passing the name of the leader board that I want to
retrieved from xbox live and it's
really just one line of code to pull back the leader board I use that context object again
...that's the interfaced all of our services...the leader board service get lear board a
...passing in the name of that leader board that's...return to me a leader board result
inside there I'm...have a collection of rows and rows going to be
one-line of the leader board so what I care about is I'm going to pull the
ranked that's first second third fourth...online the gamer
tagging person at that rank and then this item has the value...item collection
has a series of values that are the events that I told it to track for might
...board so, are, you know, that the zero with element of that is the thing that I want to display
...board so I had all those things to a collection and then display them on the
screen so if I run my app here and balance down to leader board?
It went up the server actually very fast
and, pull back the other five people that are on my leader...the global
...work currently...gamer tag and then...score according to
...how well they play the game now that's the global leader board so if you had a
really popular game obviously my...because there's only five people but if you had
a real game you might have more than five people playing so you might have thousands of people
on the leader board and you probably don't want to have someone page all the way through thousands of pages of game of
...find there so there's a couple of the methods you can do here we can call dot get leader board for social group
basing...just a leader board with just that...friends so if you want
to show them how they're competing against their friends you show them that...there's also a get leader
board with skip to user so I can say well if I'm in seven hundred
place only show me from seven hundred and that way you can immediately just jump to that
screen show where they where they rank against the rest of the world without them having to go
find out where they live in the full list of global leader boards...rewards
pull that back very easy for achievements we want to pullback list of achievements that are associated with our game it's
more information about them so as before use that same context object we're going to call the
...server this time protocol get achievements for title id
...pass in the user that we want to get the achievements for guys'll tell us if we pass in the user
...we can determine if...unlocked the achievement or not pullback all types of achievement so achievements
in challenges order them default and returned just a maximum
ten for right now...give you an achievements result which contains
an items collection inside items collection our list...equals items is
an achievement so we're going to pull the name description
the rewards data which this is currently sell to be a gamer point reward so this is the number
of points associated with that achievement whether out it's been achieved and then as with the gamer
pick you'll get a...that maps to that achievement image and if you guys play on xbox one, you know,
the achievements or these big high res...twenty by ten eighty...you can
...backgrounds in your dashboards either really high res quality images so we just pull those
things back and now we can draw that inside of our game and get a nice integrated experience.
So, I'll jump down to achievements
...web so this game has five achievements here so this again this was the name of this line
this is the description...the score the image in the background is the
image associated with the achievement so really each one of these things was, you know, justyou know,
a single line of code to retrieve the data and then whatever code you want to write to formatted and...very simple.
Now it it's interesting he just said a riots one single-line code to a
...data and then and I assure you that displaying the data as a few more and your a
...more lines of code is definitely more than one so, one of the things that's really cool it's
brand new that we're doing for...is we're adding this new feature to the xbox live is the
...call title cobble us and what this is kind of a standardize work for
certain things you do over and over your game in some cases having consistency on
how many games do it is valuable so, we're given you some of this title call-you
...such that you can actually in just a few lines of code much less than you would
...you'd...everything from scratch from scratch you can actually call specific workload, for example,
right here live profile card whenever you need to show somebody's profile we give you a
...that you can actually use...consistent all users will be familiar with it because in my
...other games so it's a good way for you to very quickly get some,
you know, profile...app and roddy without having to have a custom experience...you that's the way you want to go
one that I see a lot is multi-player in by these workflows actually kind of hard invited multiple
players, you know,...them and making sure that you can click on the right sequence
...buttons et-cetera that's actually hard so,
by as given you the flow already implemented you just...in...if you lines of code
you're done right and the same thing we do it achievements so you get the best of both worlds
on one bryan show you one line of code you get all the data you have full control over how you
render it you can create these really immersive...
experience we love those and on the other one you can say hey I don't think I need
that...this is just a profile card I can go with the standard...that users will be familiar
with few lines of code and you get the best of both worlds because you didn't have to write a lot of that code so,
that's what we have we...us now the x was obviously
k today you've seen it it's easy enough I'm sure you're wondering okay how do I get first of
all is not on the platform is not on the bits that you actually we are going to get this week it's a special
...different educated right now we still have a preview mode and the way to get it is to just
join the idea xbox program this is a feature that we have the we expect to be, you know,
available to everybody in the platform over time but this is something we haven't done in the past
...kind of going to follow I stage roll-out model we want-to make sure people succeed we
...make sure we get all the kinks out of the way and then we'll make it
available to everybody so the way to join today is pretty simple just go to http slash
xbox dot com slash id apply to join program the program is now
...updated so we can take windows thing title the bar to entries lower of courses
where to have taken...the same titles is not the same than you've had to do with consul so,
it's actually much easier for you to join and then you're going to get the benefit from there and,
the benefits are my or one of the benefits among there is that access to data is the case
...can take advantage of all the features that we just showed you so, go ahead and apply
their taking applications now...coming soon but I check with them and they said hey,
you know, we're already anybody that applies we do get back to them and all that is not something that's coming in the
future is something that we're thinking about immediately?
And, the next thing that I want to talk about why we're here is talk about the ecosystem of the
...as you see we have the api as we...is the case were pretty much ready which
...understand were very far along and now our partners
...to come along with us because we know you care about the partners like unity or
...any middleware any kind of library...using a lot of these
parser here on there's partner show...downstairs and you should go talk to them if
you interested in any of there is the case most of them will have rc bits world
going to be rolling them out in the next day or two because the whole when things should be roll-out like
today or tomorrow is a little cloudy but everybody's getting ready and we're really excited to
...you to their partners boots avenue go ask them hey when are you
...be ready here's what I needI know a few them the...today...I got the email mono game you
can download from the website already today I know coca studio which comes from microsoft has
...open tech open-source implementation it's already posted online I know you audio...
post or posted earlier today and member layer also be posting in the next day so,
pretty much when it comes to middleware we think we're ready if there's one here
...don't see listed don't think about other don't assume that is not there I just
...that we're working with
...downstairs we've talked to...and we've been...but there's a lot more coming so you see...not
...just come to act contact us afterwards and we'll make sure we track...for-you so,
that's why we're pretty ready for the ecosystem to come and
we're ready for your applications to come and we dad let's talk about we just saw
voa white house I think these people want to see a game deploy to...xbox consul right?
Yes,...
All right, yeah, I mean why else would you come to the session so how much code we have to
change to go to consul so, I'll show you I'm just going to press
at five in visual studio here with the target being.
My xbox over here which.
Is it on that's...I wanted to be on the screen?
And, while...deployed before the session.
If I...five...my still network.
When the same network I started with is the xbox on the network old-boy?
The xbox is like well there's a predeployed version of...I was going to alive but there's
the game running on xbox right now so we can so that is the exact...game
...logan code changes right so you...exacting if you
...today and...we should you saw...game which to get from windows
eight and we dropped in on windows mobile windows phone ten
no code changes...because everything was full-screen we automate a
few co changes here for input and we actually have the if you go changes for windowed for windows
...on the desktop and, that is the...you're seeing right now on the consul
no code changes and that's mono game by the way we show csharp
...type onstageeverything we showed you...and cplus-plus so, for those of you
there have cplus-plus code we just show csharp because we thought to be easy for us to type onstage and,
that's actually one of our learning titles are by the way the applications also
open-source we have a game jumping two weeks which is when we're going to release these version of the
...windows to inversion and, we usually have it on mono game unity cocoa is
so we have...platforms you can go...a sample and get a good base good baseline to get jump-start
...some of api that said he tweak twenty lines of code throughout the day so, you know,
you pry can get can be...away without as you sample so let's close
what we sakes we want-to make sure you leave we understanding where we think we're at
we understand we now have one core operating system and a
gains the whole family of windows devices ride phone.
Desktop tablet consul polo
...new right now whatever comes next you'll be there
ride we also have one application platform the
...the goes across the whole family of devices...side right there zero
...changes and we were on the consul right
...our right there you will be able to reuse your game you'll be able to take everything you have
and take it to different platforms we brought this...in
...work on to the on to windows we brought that same gain
gaming network experience on to the phone right so now you have access to xbox
...you have these very large social gaming network...you can take advantage to make sure that you
...quicker make sure you people are interacting more make sure there's more engagement
...can take advantage of everything that we
...on consul and apply those same patterns on the mobile devices or
...your desktop and cover a lot of...store there's three sessions throughout the conference at least
three that I know off that where you're going to go in the next two days learn more about the one store so,
I didn't cover a lot...a lot more than that but I can tell you these wanting a year-ago I said you
...publishing once you will publish...once that's the one thing you're going to learn...the next three days so,
hopefully that's what you want and, without...take aways pretty simple all these benefits and
all you have to do is trigger code a few places to any fifty
whatever might be a few lines of code you gotta get ready for universal if
your windows phone aid or if you're and something like windows store...for the
...make...star moving to universal immediately
ride remember we have this program over the next year we're going to tell people the first upgrade
to windows stan over the next year
it's free so we expect people to migrate quickly you wanna-be ready you
wanna-be one of those people that gets there early because those people tend to make more money so,
go ahead and go universal it's that simple for...take away I will have the slide
again for your reference you can go see all the sessions if I was to carve out a few adam to
...going-to be here onstage in the same room after us he's going to show you unity running on
unit on the...universal windows platform ...maximum...is going to talk
tomorrow about direct text twelfth much deeper for those of you that need to get down to the lower-level
barclay...jason we'll talk about our new packagings...understand sizes and how one
packets goes across all the platform so that's a really great session...screen casting
...is here healers...xbox because our...earlier today so you gotta come to
...because we owen big mixture you go to that one and,
then on friday I want to highlight this...this is the very last session and it's probably for me as a
...one of my favorite one's the one this is seven-six five...app to
...communication if I was to tell you the problems that I think people...games
...the last year-and-a-half when I have lots of partners come tell me hey this is which really
...solve everybody wanted to solve input we've solved input everybody wanted to solve
...problems they store or one of...the store and we improved a lot of them store and,
the last one that everybody asks a bodies up to
add communication right how do I do offer walls how do I communicate...my apps how do I
...promote on friday at to a...add one session...is apt to
add communications is where you learn a lot of that you're going to learn how to communicate
...apps kind of share state across apps...for everybody here has games you want
usually go published twenty games you want...offer was across them you want to make sure you communicate across
...promote them dashboard...session is going to be some make sure you domains that...
And, without with thank you very much for common we're going to put the q arco
...can evaluate while you're here because otherwise you'll forget
we take your feedback very seriously so make sure you let us know what you like when you didn't like and,
we have time for questions so please step up to the mike if you have any
questions if you don't one step up to...mike here we're going to go...
on tonight at six and we're going to be in the windows insider area tomorrow morning so,
go ahead and ask questions and...forget as a media feedback please thank you very much
With previous generations of the xbox deployment to the xbox or use of the xbox
slide
services required additional agreements and contracts that also the case of the xbox one
...is deployment and use...those api soon be open to us as
...without additional...that's a good question so the question is
hey you have apple example you might have a retail xbox at home right now that you can
...deploy too because you don't have...agreement and all that we already
...dc that later this year when...give you
...tools and utility such that you retail constant can become a dev consul so,
we're going to give you some toolkit there where you'll be able to run it and say now I can deploy from with ambitious
to you didn't see his ui but he was applying from within visual studio twenty fifteen he was doing
...five and actually deploying
and debugging and everything else we're going to give you a special little tools that you're going to be able to...with your retail
...it's coming later in a year to stay tune for that if you need immediately idea
...is the way to get some of those things today so were taken windows
...and we're going to make sure we prioritize people are going across are myriad
...broader divisivea brother family of devices.
Yeah, earlier today...the keynote we learned king use the project island would...get
...and they were going to make more...if the vision sign up page
on as well if the vision from microsoft is to support the
compilation ability to get ios schemes on to windows with the ability to
have light up features such is life tiles platform integration
and potentially xbox live integration in the form of
universal app why would why would an existing publisher like super cell or new
publishers independence actually start from the ground-up
...a universal windows up and not just...from...underwater ios.
So,...you two-part answer because I'm not I wanted...your question but tomorrow when we
talk about angle ...session we talk about angles which is...and,
I know king is going to talk about their vision there and what they're going so king started with I think it's car
would now so, the technology king started there but once they got to the platform and they
...everything we could do they say okay we're going native so
I would is a really good way for people to get started explore and...so you can continue
going that fast but we do want you to go native and we want you to get more out of platform so,
it's kind of a stepping stone...was a great way for them to get started get familiar with
the platform and then step in so I highly recommend first of all very wave
...not everybody knows...here angle is open
...on windows so, go...tomorrow because if...again where you need to learn about, you know,
open jailing windows anyway it's something that we implement from microsoft standpoint we
open-source we collaborate we google and make sure that running really great so there's a really great
session tomorrow and then you'll hear from there from even, you know, people there talk about what
king is doing and how they're already going native to get more out of the platforms so is not...what we
want to do is we want as many games for it for our users in order for us to grow
right there's growth that we need to drive in order for us to grow right now we need is many apps in
a platform as possible we need to grow the user vase and
for that if we bring some android games if we bring so
...I always games through something like...what it benefits us because the user
...growing any benefits you because they'll be more users and you'll be able to leverage your
...stopped bill more games and you'll be able to continue doing what you're doing
sets advisory question for clients, you know, if your...able to say
...technical limitations at the moment but in the future will be
results for its fundamentally just for apps or these types of games without
the additional complexity you can advice them appropriate so again I'll give you a short answer than
...am tomorrow at four thirty actually for those of you have really good
question first of all the arm with team is on the floor where you ask the experts three of them
...there we talked about it because I was involving...project that you mention ...so,
we talked about earlier we denounce when we were super excited so, there on the floor and tomorrow at four thirty
general nine lives they will have a q...with the...the pm
...would and I'll be there because I've been involved in several are with projects so if you have questions
...you want to tell them hey what's your...what works and what does send I highly
recommend you go to that I don't know where it's going to be but it's live online will take questions...be able to
answer your questions with regard to guidance come talk to me afterwards or go talk to the are with
...directly because there's...is...like everything else not everything works perfectly so, it's not
going to be although we turn it in and we, you know,
like...not going to be a we...the five and everything work there we tweaks and things that you have to learn and
he comes down to what version of say you I kid you...you know,
libraries...using what ages notifications how you up implement...you store so there's a lot of
...does make it easier I can tell you from projects that we've done we definitely
...schedules and we said ...going to take us...whatever twelve fourteen
...to rewrite and then we look at armor said we can get that with six weeks
...was...some of them was...the code...testing because that the
...weeks included are testing so it definitely makes things easier but it's not something
we would tell you all...doing native go all the way out you always get a little bit more out of
...of course so, that's kind of where we're at and,
again, feel free to come...some root questions tomorrow otherwise I'm going to be board?
Right there so.
Anything else.
Again, the one take...go ahead as your question I'm
into universe lapse if I built a gainful xbox one-on-one really high detail textures
...big measures...the windows phone will be smaller this the
...get all the extra use resources at the xone gets...so look at
the taxes well...will be intelligent packaging involved so that's a
great question so it's kind of I hey I can write against once now what about...now my...this
...game going to be twenty-five gigabytes and the...no the way you have control over how you packets
you assets our actual are packaging model this is word...session and,
...session tomorrow...packaging will give you some advise but for the last few years we already have been able
to segregate packages based on languages based on feature levels and direct text so,
you can actually go back and say here's my asses for directives feature level...which
will be what goes on the phone and then you can go back and said here's my assets for direct feature level, you know,
twelve or, you know, feature level eleven and, you'll be able to segregate those and then
our platform there's a really great java optimizing the download so we download only
which needed and we make sure we even share course libraries and we do a few other things there so
...salami and he session is going to talk a little bit about it and then if you want to dive deeper than
that after decision to say hyman said you could...tell us how to...of the knobs
and make sure that we...and there's a lot of control...you can so as long as you're willing to optimize there's a
lot of control there to make sure that things are not downloaded twice...share like if you have five
...on your windows a new in this tablet we actually make sure we download everything once and then the other users
are sharing so that we don't...don't matter everything twice...so we do really great
job optimizing that that's one thing that we're very proud of and, again, jason is a great reference for that?
If there's no more questions gc videos really,
really everything that we wanted to say about games is there there's
...many hours go watch those because we gave you a one-hour version of, you know,
eight hours worth of work over there so make sure you go to channel nine and watch them
there's links on the presentation thank you very much for coming moi.